[{"question": "Interpret sol.status = 1, where, sol = solve_ivp()", "type": "multiple_choice", "answers": [{"answer": "The solver reached the end of the integration interval.", "correct": false}, {"answer": "A termination event occurred.", "correct": true}, {"answer": "A non-termination event was evaluated.", "correct": false}, {"answer": "all of the above", "correct": false}], "tag": "scipy", "lecture_file": "05_nth_odes"}, {"question": "Assigning 'max_step = None' in solve_ivp() results in", "type": "multiple_choice", "answers": [{"answer": "Error", "correct": true}, {"answer": "The solver would determine the step size.", "correct": false}, {"answer": "The step size will be infinite.", "correct": false}, {"answer": "Need to specify 't_eval' to avoid an error.", "correct": false}], "tag": "scipy", "lecture_file": "05_nth_odes"}, {"question": "matplotlib.pyplot.axis('equal') results in", "type": "multiple_choice", "answers": [{"answer": "a square plot", "correct": false}, {"answer": "equal scaling of the axes by changing axis limits", "correct": true}, {"answer": "limits the axes to the data range", "correct": false}, {"answer": "equal scaling of the axes by changing dimensions of the plot box", "correct": false}], "tag": "matplotlib coding", "lecture_file": "05_nth_odes"}, {"question": "Assigning 'event_function.direction = -5' in solve_ivp() registers an event when", "type": "multiple_choice", "answers": [{"answer": "event value goes from positive to negative, that is, a maximum", "correct": true}, {"answer": "Error", "correct": false}, {"answer": "event value goes from negative to positive, that is, a maximum", "correct": false}, {"answer": "event value goes from negative to positive, that is, a minimum", "correct": false}], "tag": "scipy", "lecture_file": "05_nth_odes"}, {"question": "Assigning 'event_function.direction = 0' in solve_ivp() registers an event when", "type": "multiple_choice", "answers": [{"answer": "event value goes from positive to negative, that is, a maximum", "correct": false}, {"answer": "event value goes from negative to positive, that is, a minimum", "correct": false}, {"answer": "Both, a and b", "correct": true}, {"answer": "None of the above", "correct": false}], "tag": "scipy", "lecture_file": "05_nth_odes"}, {"question": "When 'dense_output = True' in 'sol = solve_ivp()', to integrate the function 'f',  then sol.sol(1)", "type": "multiple_choice", "answers": [{"answer": "would evaluate the solution at 1 if an event occurs at t=1.", "correct": false}, {"answer": "would evaluate the function f at 1 if an event occurs at t=1.", "correct": false}, {"answer": "evaluates the function f at t=1, irrespective of whether it is an event or not.", "correct": false}, {"answer": "evaluates the solution at t=1, irrespective of whether it is an event of not.", "correct": true}], "tag": "scipy", "lecture_file": "05_nth_odes"}, {"question": "What is the output of: <br><br>a = np.array([[1, 2, 3], [1, 2, 3]])<br>np.diff(a, axis = 0).shape", "type": "multiple_choice", "answers": [{"answer": "(2, 2)", "correct": false}, {"answer": "(2, 3)", "correct": false}, {"answer": "(1, 3)", "correct": true}, {"answer": "(1, 5)", "correct": false}], "tag": "numpy coding", "lecture_file": "05_nth_odes"}, {"question": "What will be the output of: <br><br>p = 0<br>while(p<0):<br>    print(p)<br>    p -= 1", "type": "multiple_choice", "answers": [{"answer": "[0, -1]", "correct": false}, {"answer": "[-1]", "correct": false}, {"answer": "loop runs for infinite iterations", "correct": false}, {"answer": "no output as loop does not run", "correct": true}], "tag": "loops coding", "lecture_file": "05_nth_odes"}, {"question": "What will be the output of:<br><br>l = [1, 2, 3]<br>a = l.reverse()<br>print(a)", "type": "multiple_choice", "answers": [{"answer": "[3, 2 ,1]", "correct": false}, {"answer": "None", "correct": true}, {"answer": "[]", "correct": false}, {"answer": "[1, 2, 3]", "correct": false}], "tag": "lists coding", "lecture_file": "05_nth_odes"}, {"question": "d^3y/dx^3 = 0<br>is equivalent to which of the following systems of differential equations?", "type": "multiple_choice", "answers": [{"answer": "dy/dx = 0<br>   da/dx = 0<br>   db/dx = 0", "correct": false}, {"answer": "dy/dx = da/dx = db/dx", "correct": false}, {"answer": "dy/dx = a<br>   da/dx = b<br>   db/dx = y", "correct": false}, {"answer": "dy/dx = a<br>   da/dx = b<br>   db/dx = 0", "correct": true}], "tag": "ode", "lecture_file": "05_nth_odes"}]